So far, we've looked at callbacks as a way to implement asynchronous non-blocking code.
Node provides another way to achieve this with Events.
Here is a callback example similar to what we've seen so far.
It's a function which invokes a callback with an array of results.
Here is a similar snippet of code written using Events.
In this case, the getThem function returns a value immediately.
The value is an instance of the EventEmmiter class.
This Results object has an On function.
Here we are specifying that for each item event,
execute this function passing in the current item.
Then, on the Done Event, or when there are no more results, invoke this function,
and if there is an error, invoke this function and pass in the error that occurred.
Some of the key differences between these two approaches are; in the Callback Model,
you make a request and provide a function to be called when the request is completed.
One request, one reply.
The Event Model, however, is more of a publish/subscribe approach.
You can invoke the On function repeatedly to provide multiple functions to invoke
on each event; in essence, subscribing to the events.
In the Callback approach, you don't receive any results until you receive all the results.
In the example above, the callback will not be invoked until the entire items array is ready.
If these items arrive slowly, the callback will not be invoked until the last item has arrived.
It also means that the getThem function will be storing the entire list of items
in memory while accumulating them prior to invoking the callback with the entire array.
On the other hand, in the evented example above, functions associated
with the item event will be invoked for each item.
This gives you the opportunity to act on the first item as soon as it arrives
and the second item and so forth.
It also means that the getThem function is not accumulating the items in memory.
Finally, the Callback scenario, if only by convention, is an all or nothing proposition.
While technically possible to invoke a callback with both error and items parameters,
this is not the convention and would not be expected.
If the error parameter is set, then the call is assumed to have failed.
In the evented scenario, however, an error is emitted as a separate event.
Notice that the item and done events do not pass in an error parameter as the first value.
In this evented approach, the error can be emitted instead of any item events
or after some item events have already been omitted.
This access to partial results may be desirable in some situations.
The EventEmitter Class is provided by Node as a construct
for building these event-driven interfaces.
The code that is subscribing to events, like the code in our last slide,
will call the On function of the EventEmitter instance
and specify the event being subscribed to.
And then the code publishing events will call the Emit function
and specify the event being emitted.
Now these events themselves are simply strings and can be of any value.
In our previous example, we defined three events; item, done, and error.
When emitting an event, you can also provide additional arguments after the event name.
These will pass as parameters to any functions subscribed to that event.
In our previous example, this included the item itself that was passed to the item event,
as well as, the error object passed to the error event.
This set of events and their arguments constitute an interface, or contract,
between the subscriber and the publisher, or emitter.
There are two common patterns I've seen for using EventEmitters in Node.
The first is as a return value from a function.
This is what we saw on the earlier slide.
In this case, an instance of EventEmitter is created directly and returned from a function.
Another common pattern is when an object extends EventEmitter
and emits events while also providing other functions and values.
Let's take a look at an example of both of these EventEmitter patterns.