So, in our EventEmitter examples, the first thing we're going to look
at is the first pattern that we talked about on the slides, which is the example
where you actually instantiate an EventEmitter and return it from a function call.
So, here we have a getResource function which takes in a number and returns an instance
of an EventEmitter that emits three events; a Start event, a Data event, and an End event.
This is a good demonstration of how these event names can be really whatever you want.
In our slides we had Item and Done, and Error.
In here we have Start, and Data, and End.
And what we're saying is whenever I see the Start event,
I want you to log this to the console.
And whenever I see the Data event, I want you to log this to the console,
including the data that was sent.
And then, on the End event, let's log this to the console.
And right now I've hidden the code inside this getResource function.
Right now we're focusing on the subscribing part.
But so for now, let's run this and see what we get.
So we'll bring this up here.
And so here you can see we have the I've Started which was the reaction to the Start event.
And then we got five Data events, and one End event that says I'm Done.
Now the five is because we passed in five and that's how many --
that's the way this function is coded.
Whatever number you pass in, that's how many data events you're going to get back.
That was us subscribing to those events and printing something out to the console.
Now let's take a look at the getResource function itself, and see what it does.
Now the first thing that it does is we instantiate a new EventEmitter.
And you'll notice that in order to do that, we had to require an EventEmitter and by doing
that we used Node's built-in events module.
Because we only wanted the EventEmitter from that events module, we specified that as part
of the required and put that in our own EventEmitter variable.
And so we instantiate one of those and then now this process nextTick is something we haven't
seen before.
In our first module we looked at SetTimeOut and SetInterval.
And process nextTick is similar but what it really says is on the very next tick
of the event loop I want you to run this function.
And in this example we're really using that to emulate an asynchronous function
because what we want is we want the return value here
to be called before we start emitting events and as would normally be the case if you were,
you know, talking to file system or a database.
So what we say is, on the next tick of the event loop I want you to emit a Start event.
It's our EventEmitter.
We're emitting a Start event.
And then now we're going to set an Interval.
And what we're saying is, every 10 milliseconds I want you to execute this function.
And then this function we're emitting our Data event.
We're keeping a count of how many Data events we've emitted so far.
We start at zero and then we keep a count.
And if the count is equal to the number that was passed in, we're going to emit an End event
and then clear that interval to stop the function from being executed.
This is an example of the first pattern of using an EventEmitter.
Now let's take a look at the second pattern.