In this second example, we're going to take a look at the second pattern we discussed earlier
where we have an object that extends the EventEmitter class.
So what we've done is we've taken our original example and basically cut it in half,
and we've taken the code that emits the events and separated it
out into a separate JavaScript file.
So let's start by taking a look at that file.
So here you'll see we have a function called Resource which takes a number,
and I've hidden the contents of the function for now.
We'll get to that in just a minute.
But what this function basically does --
this is ourObject, and ourObject extends or inherits from EventEmitter.
So in order to do that, we're using Node's util module which we've required here.
It's a built-in module and it has an Inherits function.
And what we've said is, we want our resource object to inherit from the EventEmitter object,
which gives us access to the On function and the Emit function, and also, because we want scripts
that included this file as a module, to have access to our resource object.
We set module.exports equal to resource.
Now if we look down inside the code for the Resource function,
you'll see that it's almost identical to what we saw in our getResource function.
process.netTick is here.
The Events are emitted here.
The only difference is that because in our previous example,
we were instantiating an EventEmitter and using that instantiated variable
to call the Emit function, in this case
because our Resource function inherits from EventEmitter.
It is our Resource function that's doing the emitting of the events and so we need to use the
"This" variable to access the current resource that needs to do the emitting.
This is all packaged up in a Resource.js.
So now let's take a look at the JavaScript code that is using this.
In our main script file we have a Require statement and here,
because we're requiring another JavaScript file in our project, we have the dot slash
and then the name of the file which is Resource.js,
and we're storing it in a Resource variable.
So in this example, instead of simply calling a function and getting an instance
of an EventEmitter back, we're instantiating our Resource object and getting
that back here and the variable Are.
But once we do that, we're subscribing to the same events we did before.
So let's run this and see if we get what we expect.
( Typing Sounds)
And, yes, as you would expect, we're getting the -- I've started, the Start event,
and then seven data events because we passed in a seven, and then the End event.
So the net effect, at least in the console, is the same.
But these are the two types of patterns that you'll see from time to time.
You may have an actual object that you instantiate that emits Events,
or you may have a case where you call a function and get an EventEmitter back.