Building on the concept of an EventEmitter is something that Node calls a stream.
A stream extends the EventEmitter class
and implements an agreed-upon set of events and other functions.
These events provide a unified abstraction for dealing with multiple types of dataflow,
including network traffic such as; http and tcp traffic, File I/O,
standard in/out and error, and more.
Each stream is an instance of either a ReadableStream,
meaning something that you would read from, a WriteableStream,
something that you would write to, or both.
Also, because of the standard events and functions exposed in both Readable
and WriteableStreams, a ReadableStream can be piped to a WriteableStream.
This is conceptually similar to piping commands in Unix where the data read
from the ReadableStream is piped to the WriteableStream.
Node handles the backpressure and to address the scenario
where a ReadableStream provides data faster than a WriteableStream can consume it.
The interface of a ReadableStream includes a Boolean indicating whether the stream is
currently readable or not; a series of events that are emitted when new data arrives
or when there is no more data, etc.
; a series of functions to pause, resume,
and destroy the stream; as well as the pipe function.
And the interface to a WriteableStream includes a similar Boolean indicating whether this stream
is currently writeable; events that are emitted such as drain when it is safe to write
to this stream; and pipe when this stream has been passed to a ReadableStream's pipe function;
functions to write data to the stream; and to terminate it.
While you can certainly interact with streams directly by subscribing to events
and invoking functions directly, the real power of streams comes from the pipe function.
Now that we've briefly covered some of the functions and events and Readable
and WriteableStreams, let's see how these work together to provide the pipe functionality.
When you invoke the pipe function on a ReadableStream,
you pass as a parameter the WriteableStream you want to pipe to.
This in turn emits the pipe event on the WriteableStream.
The pipe function then begins an orchestration of events and functions between the two streams.
When data arrives to the ReadableStream, the data event is emitted and the write function
on the WriteableStream is invoked with this data.
If at some point the write function returns a false value indicating
that no more data should be written, the pause function
of the ReadableStream is called "to stop the flow of data."
Then, once the WriteableStream is ready to receive more data, the drain event is emitted
and the resume function on the ReadableStream is invoked.
Once the ReadableStream is finished, the End event is emitted and the End function
on the WriteableStream is invoked.
This elaborate dance happens behind a very simple interface and one that is consistent
across network, file, and process communication.
Let's take a look at some Stream examples.