So first, we'll take a look at a ReadableStream.
So to do this, we're going to use the Request Module.
And if you remember from Module Two the Request Module is a third-party module
that we've installed from the npm registry.
We've already done that here and we're going to Require and Request
and store it in the Request variable.
One of the nice things about Request is it understands and makes very good use of streams.
And so here, by simply calling Request and passing it in the name
of a URL, it will return to us a stream.
And then, because, if you remember, streams inherit from EventEmitters,
we can use the On function to subscribe to some of the events
that are emitted from a ReadableStream.
So the Data event is emitted whenever new Data has been received, and the End event is emitted
when there's no more data to be read.
And so we subscribe to these two events and what Request does is the stream
that it gives you back is actually the body of the Response of the Request.
So, in our example, it should be the html of the Pluralsight Homepage, and so as the Data
for that Homepage comes back, we'll get some number of Data events and the function
that we're asking it to invoke on the Data event.
The parameter that's passed to it is the actual Data that it received.
And so we want to log that to the console, and then our tags --
or if you want to call them that, that we added.
So let's go back to the bottom.
Done is there.
So our End event was emitted and we printed Done.
Now let's scroll back through and look for our Data with the angle brackets.
So if we see (scrolling sound) -- there's one.
So that means this was the start of one of the chunks.
(Scrolling sound) And we keep scrolling.
And there's another one.
(Scrolling sound) And so on and so forth.
So what happens is as the html is being returned from the http request,
those Data events are being fired and pieces of the html are being sent
to the functions being registered to that Data event.
And, of course, we're just printing them to the console.
This is how you would interact with the ReadableStream.
Next we'll take a look at a WriteableStream.
So in this case, the example we're going to use
for the WriteableStream is processed.standardout.
The Process module has several streams that it makes available.
One is StandardIn.
One is StandardOut and another is StandardError.
So, in this case, we wanted a WriteableStream, so we're going to use StandardOut.
And in this case what we're doing is we're simply writing
out Hello, and then writing out World.
And we're also going to inspect the Boolean variable just to make sure
that this StandardOut really is Writeable.
So, let's run this.
And so it's simple enough.
Is it Writeable?
Yes, and prints out True.
And the Write function does what you would expect.
It takes each of those and just simply writes them to StandardOut.