So now we're going to take a look at piping a ReadableStream to a WriteableStream.
And so we're basically going to combine the previous two examples together.
Here, in this case, we have our Request module that we've required
and stored in our Request to variable.
And similar to our ReadableStream example, we're going to call Request
on the Pluralsight Homepage, and store that stream that's returned in the Variable S.
But now, instead of listening for events on that ReadableStream,
we're going to simply call the pipe function, and we're going to pipe it
to our WriteableStream, which in this case, we're going to use the WriteableStream
from our second example, Process.StandardOut.
And so what this should do is take the html returned from the Request
and simply pipe it to the console.
So let's run this and see what we get.
Piping the Request to StandardOut simply dumps everything
that came back just straight to StandardOut.
Now, of course, you could also simply chain these together and call Request
and because Request is going to return to you a stream you could simply,
on the end of the Request, do .pipe and then pipe it to the WriteableStream.
This will, in essence, do the exact same thing as the code above it that's commented out.
But let's just run it to prove that to ourselves.
Yep, and so it does exactly the same thing.
Now here is an example that's a little bit different than before.
So now what we're going to do is take the same Request of the same Webpage.
But now, instead of piping it to the console,
what we're going to do is pipe it to a file on the file system.
And so to do this, we're using the FS module, which is another built-in Node module,
and we're bringing it in and storing it as the FS variable, and FS is for the File System.
And so here what we're doing is calling the CreateWriteStream function on the FS module
which says I want you to create me a writeable stream that will store the contents
in this file and return me that stream.
Because the CreateWriteStream function returns a stream,
we've simply put that function invocation as the parameter to the pipe function.
So here we're saying, okay, I want you to request this Website and I want you to pipe it
to the stream returned by the CreateWriteStream function which will create this file.
So when we're done, we should be able to run this one line of code, download this html
from their Homepage, and write it to a file.
Let's try that.
( Typing Sounds )
It ran and it's complete, so now let's do an LS and see what we have.
So we have our Pluralsight.html file.
In fact, if we (typing sounds) -- we can see that it does have a size to it,
and if we want to add to the console we can...
( Typing Sounds )
We can see that that file does indeed contain html from the Pluralsight Homepage.
So, in one line of code you can download a Webpage and write it to a file.
So what we're going to do for our last example is take our previous one one step further.
If you remember from our slides, we mentioned
that a stream can either be a ReadableStream, a WriteableStream, or both.
In this case we're going to show a stream that is both readable and writeable.
So what we've done is taken our Request, a Website -- or a Webpage --
and write it to a file, and we've injected into the middle of it the ability
to gzip the data on the way into the file.
And so what we have is Node has another built-in module called zlib, and so we've required that.
And what we have is our Request function which we never turned to stream,
and so on that stream we're calling pipe, and then what we're passing
to pipe is actually the results of zlib.creategzip.
So what create.gzip does is return a stream that's both readable and writeable
that will read in uncompressed content and output compressed content.
And so we call that function.
We'll get that stream back.
We pass that to pipe.
The pipe function, as its return value, will return the stream that you passed into pipe.
And the reason that it works that way is explicitly so you can chain these together.
So, when we pass in the stream that was returned from the create.gzip function into pipe,
the return value of this pipe function is actually the stream.
So on that stream, we can call pipe.
And pipe that output to our CreateWriteStream function call.
But in this case, we're going to name the file Pluralsight.html.gz
because in this case it's gzipped.
So, we'll execute our request, get the Data back,
pipe it through our gzip stream and then pipe it onto a file.
So, let's run this and see what we get.
( Typing Sounds )
Okay. So it's done.
Now let's do an LS (typing sounds) and see what we have.
Okay. So now we do have a Pluralsight.html.gz.
If you'll notice, it is a good bit smaller than the .html which would lead us
to assume that it is obviously compressed.
But now, let's actually look at the contents of that file and just to prove it to ourselves.
So if we use a zcat command...
( Typing Sounds )
...to print that out.
And there you go.
You'll see that it is the actual html.
You can get very, very creative with these chaining of the pipes together,
and it just shows how much you can do in a very small amount of code
with the benefit of this pipe command.
And if you remember from the slides of all the back and forth with the pause, and drain,
and resume, and all that -- I mean, all of that is in place here in-between each one
of these pipes to manage the flow of the data from one to the other.