Paul O'Fallon: Hello, my name is Paul O'Fallon and I'd like to welcome you
to the course, An Introduction to Node.js Module 2, Modules require an NPM.
In this module we're going to cover how to include Node modules in your application.
We'll then look at the three most common sources of Node modules and we'll wrap
up with a discussion on how to create and publish your own Node modules.
So let's get started.
Modules are the way to bring external functionality to your Node application.
The require function loads a module and assigns it to a variable for your application to use.
Modules make their functionality available
by explicitly exporting it for use in other applications.
A module can export specific variables and these variables can also be functions.
Sometimes a module may export an object which you can instantiate in your code.
Here too, you'll notice an informal naming convention.
A module which simply exports a set of variables is often assigned
to a camel case variable starting with a lowercase letter; foo in this example.
However, a module which is designed
to be instantiated will be assigned a camel case variable
with an initial capital; Bar in this example.
Finally, there may be cases where you only need a single variable
or function out of a large module.
You can import just the one function you need
by specifying the variable name immediately after the require function call.
There are three main sources of modules that you can bring
into your project with the require function.
The first is Node's built-in modules.
While Node provides a few functions in its global name space such as set timeout
and set interval, there are many modules that shift with Node that must be explicitly included
in your project in order to be used.
These module names passed to the require function are simple string identifiers,
such as fs here.
Some of the built-in Node modules include fs for accessing the file system, http for creating
and responding to http requests, crypto for performing cryptographic functions
and os for accessing attributes of the underlying operating system.
Let's take a look at some examples of using require
to access Node's built-in modules (silence).