Okay, so we're going to take a look at a very simple example
of using Node's built-in modules and including those via require.
So, here at the top of our script you'll see the require function,
require and then here we're just requiring the os module.
Now, to get access to the os module we didn't have to do anything special
in our Node installation, it just comes with Node, but it's not included in your project
by default so we have to include it by calling require os
and we're assigning that to the os variable.
This is a module that will give you some information
about the operating system that your script is running on.
In this case we're going to print out the host name, we're going to print
out the 15 minute load average, which is the third element in the array,
and we're going to print out the free memory and the total memory.
And I have this little function here just to convert what it gives me back to Megabytes.
So, it's really as simple as that for the os module.
Obviously as we go through the remaining course modules we're going
to be diving into more of Node's modules.
The os is one of the more simple ones, but it gives you an idea of the require.
So now let's run this and take a look at the console.
So you'll see the host name, the load average and then the memory statistics here.
So, the os module is a handy way to get access to this information in your Node application,
but more importantly this is a very simple example of how you would require
in an external module using require, assign it to a variable and then use it in your script.