Another use of the require function is to access functionality located
within other files in your project.
In Node's module system each of your JavaScript files is a module
and can expose functionality to be required by other files.
This is a great way to modularize your code, making it easier to develop and maintain.
In this case the require syntax is more rich and can include file system-like semantics.
For example, you can require a file in the same directory, in a subdirectory,
or in another navigable directory.
Note the dot slash prefix is always required in this case
and the js suffix of the file is omitted.
Aside from the syntax of the module name, require operates the same as before,
meaning that you can still require a single variable from another JavaScript file like this.
The way you make variables available to other JavaScript files is
by assigning values to the module.exports object.
For example, let's take a look at one.js.
It has the variable count assigned the value of two and doIt assigned a function.
We've made the function available to external callers by adding it to module.exports.
Similarly the variable foo with the value bar is also exported.
Now, in two.js we require the file one.js using this syntax.
Next we can invoke the function doIt since it was exported in one.js
and we have similar access to the foo.
However, since the count variable in one.js was not exported it is not available in two.js.
Only those variables defined as a part of module.exports are available externally.
Let's take a look at an example of exporting and requiring variables
between JavaScript files (silence).