Okay, so now we're going to take a look at using require
to import one JavaScript file into another JavaScript file.
And to start off we're going to take a look at a file called mathfun.js
and what we've done is we've taken the evenDoubler function from our last module
and brought it forward here and put it in mathfun.js and really this maxTime
and the function definition are identical to what we looked at last time.
But now we've added a line here and assigned evenDoubler to module.exports and --
which should make it available to other scripts that want to use it.
And then while we were here we decided to go ahead
and just set a foo variable to the value of bar.
Treated as a module this has exported two variables evenDoubler and foo.
So now let's go see what it looks like to require that in another script.
So up here you can see we've called the require function and passed in dot slash mathfun.
The dot slash says look in the current directory and find me a JavaScript file named mathfun.
Now we don't put the .js here, but that's assumed.
Process results and the four loop, that's all just really a carryover from the prior video
so I'm not going to go through that.
But what you'll notice here is when I invoke evenDoubler now, I am prefixing it with mathfun
because that function has actually surfaced through this variable, mathfun.
So we're calling it mathfun.evenDoubler, just like we called it evenDoubler before and then
down here we're also going to try to call the foo variable in mathfun
which we should get back bar for that, and even though it shouldn't work we're going to go ahead
and try to print out a value of maxTime.
If you'll remember from mathfun js, it is set here but it's not exported.
So it should not be visible inside of this file.
So let's run this (silence).
Okay, so I'm not going to go over the bulk of the output,
this is just a carryover from last time.
You'll see we printed out our invocations and then we printed out our results down here.
But you'll notice that the function calls were made so the calls to evenDoubler were made
in the mathfun module and also when we accessed the foo variable we did get the value bar back,
like we expected and when we tried to access maxTime we got undefined
because that variable was not exported.
So, that is a quick look at what it looks like to import one JavaScript file
into another using the require statement.