The final source for Node modules we're going
to cover is the Node Package Manager or NPM registry.
It is home to many third party modules available for download and use in your Node applications.
Modules are installed from the NPM registry
by using the NPM command that is installed with Node.
NPM install and then the module name will download and install this module
into a Node modules folder inside your project.
Modules that have been downloaded and installed this way can be required
with the same simple string identifiers as Node's built-in modules.
Node understands how to traverse the Node modules folder structure
to load the appropriate JavaScript code.
Similar to loading a single function from a file, you can also load a specific file
from a module by calling require with the relative past to that file
within the modules directory structure.
While technically feasible, this should be done with extreme care.
Pulling a single file from deep within the directory structure
of a third party module may introduce a level of coupling that the module author never intended.
Finally, some Node modules provide more than variables
and functions you can access within your Node application.
They also provide utilities you can invoke from the command line.
Since these modules have a scope beyond any one application,
you will want to install them outside of your current projects directory tree.
You can do this by invoking NPM install with the dash G flag for global.
This will install the module along with the appropriate command line executable on your path
so they are available both inside and outside of your project.
Some examples of Node modules that provide command line utilities include the express web
framework, the Mocha test framework and the module provided
by Microsoft for their Azure cloud platform.
Let's take a look at installing some third party modules using NPM (silence).