So now we're going to take a look at using the Node Package Manager or NPM registry to search
for and install third party modules for use within our Node applications.
So a great place to look for modules that might be of interest to you is the NPMJS.org website
where you can see statistics about the module ecosystem in general and also some stats
about some particular modules, the most depended upon modules
which arguably would be the most popular modules.
They're the ones that other modules depend on the most and ones
that are most recently updated etcetera.
Now the module that we're interested in this time is the request module,
which is the second most depended upon module.
And when looking at any particular module you'll be able to go to a webpage,
see some download statistics and just some general information
about the module including their read me file.
And so we've decided we would like to install the request module,
which is a simplified http request client.
So let's go back to our project and here now we have a very simple script which uses require
to load the request module and assign it to the variable request.
We won't go into a whole lot of detail about what it does.
I do suggest you look into it further; it really is a great module.
It's also very simple to use and simple to explain.
So, if you invoke the request function and the first parameter you pass in the URL
that you would like to receive, then the second parameter is a callback.
The callback takes three parameters; of course it follows the Node convention
of taking the error parameter as the first parameter to the callback
and then it has two other parameters in the callback; the response object and the body,
which is the text of the response.
So now if we were to run it right now we would get an error
because we haven't actually downloaded
and installed the request module from the NPM registry.
So, we need to get it and download and install it locally and the way that we'll do that is
with the NPM command from the command line.
First we need to be sure that we're in the right directory
where the script file is that we want to run.
And so, we need to go down into (typing) - and so now we can run the NPM install command
and we want to install request (silence).
Okay, and so now that the module's been installed we should be good to go and we can try
to run our script and see what we get (silence).
And so what we have is the html and JavaScript that is the Pluralsight homepage,
but we did that by using the request function which came as a part of the request module.
This was a third party module that we downloaded from the NPM registry.