Publishing your own modules to the NPM registry is very easy
and is a great way to share your work with others.
It's as simple as adding one extra file to your Node project and a couple of extra NPM commands.
The file you need to add to your project root is package.json.
This file describes your modules to NPM and specifies how they should be installed
when downloaded from the registry.
It only has a couple of required fields; name and version.
NPM encourages the use of semantic versioning in your version numbers.
There are another set of optional fields that are primarily used
to describe your module on the NPM website.
These will help others find your module as well as your source code repository.
If your module has any dependencies, you should specify those here as well.
You'll notice that exact version numbers are not required, ranges are also supported.
When NPM installs your module it will also download and install its required dependencies.
Main is where you define the entry point into your module.
This is what is executed when someone requires your module.
Once you have this file ready you'll need to run NPM add user
to create an account on the NPM registry.
With that in place you simply run NPM publish dot
from your project's root directory to publish the module to NPM.
One additional step I recommend is to move to an empty directory, run NPM install on your module
and try to use it in a sample Node application.
I know from experience that it is easy to upload a broken module and not realize it because all
of the unit tests passed in the working directory before you publish it.
So, to conclude; in this module we discussed how to include Node modules
in your project using the require statement.
The three common sources of Node modules; the built-in modules,
your own applications JavaScript files and the NPM registry.
And we wrapped up with the brief discussion on how to define
and publish your own module to the NPM registry.
I hope this module has been a useful introduction
to the Node's modules, the require statement and NPM.
Thank you.