"Node.js" is a server-side "JavaScript" platform.
It was first introduced to the community by its creator, Ryan Dahl,
at the "2009 JSConf.eu Conference".
Its presentation was received with a standing ovation.
Since that time, "Node" has continued to evolve, with contributions from the community as well
as the project's primary sponsor, cloud computing Company Joyent.
"Node" is among the most popular projects on "GitHub", often beating out other heavyweights
such as "jQuery" and "Ruby on Rails".
At a high level, "Node" is comprised of three building blocks.
The first is "Lib UV", a high performance, cross-platform evented IO library.
It's a fairly new addition to "Node", and replaces
or abstracts several UNIX-only libraries once directly required by the project.
"Lib UV" was built as a part of porting "Node.js" to the "Windows" environment.
Next is "V8".
This is Google's "JavaScript" engine, the same engine found in their Chrome web browser.
The "Node" team makes every effort to leverage "V8" out of the box within "Node".
This makes it easier for the team to include updated versions of "V8" in each release
of "Node", and thereby benefit from Google's continuous innovation
of their "JavaScript" engine.
The last component of "Node" is the custom "C++"
and "JavaScript" code developed specifically for the "Node" platform itself.
These three things together make up the "Node.js" platform.