There are several ways to get "Node.js".
There are installers and binaries available for download at nodejs.org,
and "Node" is available via many common "Linux" package managers.
Of course, the source code is also available if you'd like to download and build it yourself.
One handy way I've found to manage my "Node" installations in a "Linux"
or "Mac" environment is with "NVM",
a tool developed by Tim Caswell in the spirit of Ruby's "RVM".
It can be cloned directly from "GitHub", and used to install
and manage any number of "Node" versions.
Because "Node" is evolving so rapidly, tools like "NVM" can be helpful not only
with the manual task of downloading and building a new release, but also by allowing you
to rapidly switch executables for testing your code
against multiple versions of "Node" all on one system.
Here you see the steps to get started.
After cloning, simply source the shell script and run "NVM Install" with a version number.
You can switch versions with the "NVM Use" statement, and you can set your default version
of "Node" with the "NVM Alias Default" statement.
Let's take a look at using "NVM" to install "Node".