So now we're going to take a look at installing "Node" on an
"Aboon 2" "Linux" instance using "NVM".
Now, as I mentioned, the absolute easiest way to install "Node" on "Linux" is just
by using the version that comes with the "Package Manager".
So let's take a look real quick at how we would do that.
First, let's search for that package.
( Typing on Keyboard )
And here you can see that there are several "Node.js" packages that we could install,
so if we wanted to install "Node", we could simply install the
"Node.js" package, and it would be available here.
Now if you want to manage multiple versions, or if you want to stay more current
with the latest version of "Node", you can use a tool like "NVM" to manage those yourself.
So let's look at doing that, so, as I mentioned, you'll want to first clone the repository
of "NVM" from "GitHub", and to do that you'll need to have the
"Git" client installed on your machine.
And when you do, you'll run a command like this.
So here we're going to clone it into an "NVM" directory.
Okay, so now we have it cloned, if we look in there (typing
on keyboard), we have some shell scripts.
And before we actually have the command available to use,
we need to source the appropriate shell script so let's do that.
( Typing on Keyboard )
Okay, now "NVM" should work.
Yes, and there are all the commands that are available with "NVM".
So if we do "NVM LS", you'll see we don't have any versions installed yet,
so let's actually install a version.
( Typing on Keyboard )
You'll see that install went very quickly,
and that's because for the more recent versions they actually have the binary for a lot
of platforms available to download, so I didn't even have to compile it;
all I had to do is just download it.
And that makes it really easy to install multiple versions,
particularly when they are the more recent versions.
And so if I do "NVM LS", now you'll see I have two versions,
and I'm currently using the last one I installed, which was 8.15.
So if I want to install an older version, let's say a 0.6 version, of "Node",
for that I'll have to compile it.
In order to do that on "Linux", I'll have
to have the appropriate compilers and what not installed.
It's much like you would expect to build any "C++" project.
( Typing on Keyboard )
So even though it is downloading and compiling, "NVM" takes care of all of that for you as long
as the appropriate packages are installed on your system.
( Silence )
So now this build process is going to go on for quite some time.
Okay, so the compilation is done.
"NVM" is telling us that we're now using "Node" version 0.6.9.
So now an "NVM LS" will show us three versions,
where our current one again is the last one we installed.
If I want to switch between versions, well, let's just --
let's verify that what we see is true.
So if I do "Node-V", 0.6.9.
Now to switch versions of "Node", I can simply go to "NVM Use 0.8.15",
and if I do "Node-View now", you'll see 0.8.15.
So I can switch that easily.
But if you're like me, 99% of the time you're going to be wanting
to use the same version of "Node".
You don't necessarily want to have to set it every time.
Well, "NVM" makes that easy by giving you the ability to alias to a default version.
And so by doing that, what that means is, whenever "NVM" is sourced,
it will give you that version by default.
Now you can use aliases for more than this, but this is really the case where I use aliases.
So if I type "NVM Alias Default Version 0.8.15", now the default is 8.15.
So now that we have "Node" installed, let's actually run it (typing on keyboard).
So if you execute "Node" without any script name,
it will dump you into a "Read eval print loop", or "REPL", where you can interact
with "Node" from the "Command Prompt".
Obviously, the most trivial example would be to just do a "Console.log" (typing
on keyboard), and it prints to the console.
So that's one way to play around with it for very simple experiments with "Node".
So let's create a file, and give ourselves something a little more substantial (typing
on keyboard).
We're going to try to set "Time-out", and so let's just try one
of those here (typing on keyboard).
So we're going to call -- have "Set Time-out" call a function (typing on keyboard),
and print the word "world" (typing on keyboard) after one second.
But we're going to have it immediately print the word "hello",
and so let's try that (typing on keyboard).
And so this script was almost identical to one that Ryan Dahl did in his 2009 demo of "Node".
Okay, so now let's try to run an example
that will do a little more than simply set a time-out.
Let's try to spin up a very simple HTTP server.
Now on the "Node" home page, you'll see the code for a very simple web server
that just prints out "Hello, world."
So what I've done is I've copied that and pasted it into a script called "Server JSConf.eu".
Now the only thing I've changed is I've taken off the IP address
and left just the port number.
We'll go into more in a later module about what this is really doing,
but just take it for granted that we're creating a web server
and we are writing back a text-plain header and sending the text "Hello, World."
And this web server is going to listen on port 1337, and it's also going
to print something out to the console.
So if we run that (typing on keyboard), and we go to the host name of this VM
at that address, and hit "Return", let's see.
And you'll see we get "Hello, World."
So it's printing that out, very, very simple example, but I mean,
it's a running web server in a few lines of code.