You can, of course, edit "JavaScript" files for "Node" in your favorite text editor
and run them from the command line.
However, many of the examples in this course will be shown using the free version
of the web-based "Cloud9 IDE".
It provides browser support for many of the common editing, running,
and debugging tasks you'll do as a part of "Node" development.
In fact, much of "Cloud9" itself was written in "Node.js".
In this screenshot, you can see some of the syntax highlighting,
and even code completion support, for "Node.js" applications.
Let's take a quick look,, and familiarize ourselves with some
of the features provided by "Cloud9".
So to get started with "Cloud9", you'll want to go to the home page, which is at c9.IO.
Now once you're here, you can sign up by creating an account directly on "Cloud9",
or log in with your "GitHub" or "Bitbucket" account.
Now I chose to associate my login on "Cloud9" with my "GitHub" account, and,
since I've been here before, it already knows who I am and it's asking me to go
to "My Dashboard", so let's click here and do that.
So here you can see "My Dashboard".
What it has down the left is the projects that I'm currently editing,
or currently have active on "Cloud9".
But because I've associated with my "GitHub" account,
it also has all of my projects that are on "GitHub".
But what we want to do here is we're going to go into the project that I've created that has all
of the simple code for this course, and that's this "PS Intro to Node", so let's click on that.
And we'll want to start editing.
So once we get into a particular workspace, it should look familiar to you
if you've used any other "IDE" before.
It shares a lot in common with, say, "Visual Studio" or "Eclipse".
It's got a series of menus across the top that you can use to do various functions within the
"IDE", but one in particular that's unique to "Cloud9" is this "Share" function.
You can invite someone by email, "Twitter", or "Facebook" to come
and co-develop a project with you.
And I've used this once before and it's really,
really impressive to see somebody else editing your file, and running it,
and watching the output in the console from someone else running it.
That's pretty impressive.
Now over here on the side you'll see the tree structure
for our project, and the folders and files.
But you can do several other things with this sidebar if that's not what you want to see.
You can only show the open files, or you can set your "Run" in "Debug Options".
And here is where if you wanted to run it in a different version of "Node", you could do that.
So here they have "Node" 8.X and 6.X. or if this was a "PHP" project,
you could set that there as well.
Now if you'll remember, on our "Linux" instance, where we were using "NVM" to switch
between version 8 and version 6 of "Node", and you had to download and compile version 6,
you don't have to do any of that here.
You can just pick the one that you want to use, and it's there for you.
And then, when you're ready to deploy, you can deploy to a couple
of different providers directly from "Cloud9".
So you can deploy to "Heroku" or "Windows Azure" directly from the "IDE".
And then, of course, there's a lot of settings that you can set about the
"IDE" to tailor it to your liking.
So then here is a tabbed-based editing window
which you would be familiar with from other "IDEs".
Now it's one other thing that's kind of interesting is that, in particular for "Node",
is that the "Cloud9 IDE" has pretty good support for code completion and syntax highlighting
for "Node" -- well, syntax highlighting for "JavaScript" and code completion for "Node" --
so, for instance, if I go and type "Console.log",
you'll see how it's giving me assistance there.
In fact, if I just do "Consoles" and then stop, I can scroll through the various functions
that it has, and, you know, get some extra information about those,
and some documentation here as well, and actually some assistance.
If I've left a syntax error here, I can get some guidance as well.
And then, down here at the bottom has a console and then an output window,
so in the console you can enter a lot of different commands, some of which are kind
of "UNIX" style commands, and some are special to this console.
So if we type in "Help", we can see the commands that are here, and some of them about navigating
to tabs are specific to "Cloud9", but then also, if you scroll up further,
you'll see things like "LS" and "MV", so more "UNIX" style commands.
So if you're more comfortable with typing things,
and want to do less mouse movement, you can do that.
It also supports a lot of keyboard shortcuts, so "Control-S" to save a file and what not.
If you run an application -- so let's run this one, just super simple, we'll save it first;
now we'll run it -- and you can see that now we're in the
"Output" tab here, and we're seeing "Hello, world."
Now a couple of these -- a couple lines will show
up whenever you run a "Node" code on "Cloud9".
In this case, we're just printing to the console so they don't apply, but they're here anyway,
so it's reminding us that we should use "Process EMV Port" and "IP"
as the host import of our scripts.
And then if I wanted to see the web App that I was writing
in "Cloud9", I could click on this link.
So now let's run just a barely, slightly more complicated example.
Let's do that "Set Time-out" that we did on the "Linux" VM.
( Typing on Keyboard )
And we'll run that, and there you go.
You see "Hello, world" in the output.
Now let's go back to the "Node" home page and grab that code
and try creating a simple HTTP server.
So here we are again on the "Node" home page.
Let's scroll down and grab this code again, and we will paste it here.
Now the reminder it gave us down here matters, so let's go ahead and, since we're not going
to be necessarily running it at that host and IP, let's take that out.
And let's grab these descriptors they suggested that we use
for these variables for the port and the IP.
I'll paste those in, and now we'll run this.
And you can see it actually pulled it up in a browser here.
If we want to pull it up in a separate tab, or separate window, we can just click on this...
( Background Sounds )
...and there you go, "Hello, World."
Now the host name of the instance is "Cloud9" or "C9.io", then my username,
and then the name of the workspace.
And it's "Hello, world", and that is what's running here, and so it's a very simple way
to come in, sign up, to get yourself a development environment and a web server.
Most of the examples that we do in this course, we're going to do in "Cloud9".
It would be great for you to go ahead and sign up for a free account and keep up.