One of the key concepts "Node" brings from the browser to "JavaScript"
on the server is the "Event Loop".
In the browser, the "Event Loop" is constantly listening for DOM events,
so just key presses or mouse clicks.
Similarly, Node's "Event Loop" is constantly listening for events on the server side.
These events can be externally generated, such as incoming HTTP requests or TCP connections,
or they can be timers and other internal events generated by your "Node" application itself.
Additionally, other events may be triggered on the response
to a request against an external resource.
For example, asking "Node" to open a file for reading will fire an event
when the file is opened and ready.
Sending a message to an external process will fire an event when the message has been sent.
And making a request of a network resource, such as another web server, will fire an event
when the HTTP response is received.
A key point is that each of these are handled as discrete events in "Node".
In fact, the events will very likely interleave each other.
For example, in this diagram, a timer event is received between the request for a file
and when the file is ready for reading, and both TCP
and HTTP events are received while we're sending a message to an external process.
"Node" itself doesn't pause and wait for any of these requests to complete.
It simply continues to react to events as they arrive.
A common example to demonstrate this non-blocking,
event-driven approach is a web application that fetches data from a data base.
The application raises an event when an HTTP request is received.
This event generates a query to the data base for some information.
Once "Node" receives an event back from the data base that the query is complete,
an HTTP response is formulated and sent to the caller.
While it is waiting for the response from the data base, however, "Node" is not blocked
and is free to handle additional requests.
Here you can see that it receives a second request while still waiting for the first one
to complete, and so on, and so forth.
This non-blocking approach is fundamental to "Node", and differentiates it
from the more traditional, server-side programming model that requires you
to manage multiple threads to achieve this type of concurrency.