Writing code that operates in this non-blocking,
asynchronous environment requires a different way of thinking.
Here is a typical approach to querying a data base,
shown using some JavaScript-looking pseudo code.
Each function returns a value before the next function is called.
Each statement builds on the results of the prior one.
First, we connect to a data base.
Then we use that connection to create a statement.
From that statement, we execute a query and get back a set of results.
Finally, we iterate over those results.
"Node.js" code that accomplishes this task would look quite different in this case
because each function returns almost immediately,
before the actual work has been done.
We have to find other ways to convey the ordering of our statements.
If you look at the "Get DB" connection function, you'll see in this case it takes two parameters.
The first is the same connection string as before, but the second parameter is a function.
What we're saying, in effect, is, "Get a connection to the data base,
and once you have it, call this function and pass it the connection you just created."
By crafting the statement this way, we've left "Node" free to do other work while it's waiting
for the data base connection to be established.
The "Create Statement" function is written similarly,
except in this case the only parameter is the function
to call once the statement has been created.
These two functions are examples of using call-backs
to write code that will run asynchronously.
However, lest you think functions with return values have disappeared altogether,
you'll notice that the "Execute Query" function does indeed return a value.
In this case, the results object returned
from the function does not immediately contain the results of the data base query.
It is a special object called an "Event Emitter", which is capable of emitting events
in the future, when each row of the query result becomes available.
Here we're telling "Node" to invoke a function
when each row event is omitted by the results object.
We'll learn more about event emitters in a later module.
"Node" has adopted some conventions around its use of call-backs,
and it's important to cover those briefly here.
They'll help set the stage for many of the examples we'll cover in upcoming modules.
Let's start with a function called "Git-Stuff".
It takes two parameters.
The first one is a regular input parameter, and the second is the call-back function
to invoke once the "Git-Stuff" function has completed.
A "Node" convention is that the call-back parameter is always the last parameter passed
to the asynchronous function.
Here that call-back is a named function called "Handle Results".
Another convention around the use of call-backs is error handling.
The first value passed to the call-back should always be an error parameter.
While "Node" does support JavaScript's "try catch" syntax, it's much more common
to report an error by passing a value as the first parameter to the call-back.
Additionally, it's very convenient to verify whether a function succeeded by checking
for an undefined or "False-E" error value at the top of your call-back function.
In this example, we used a named variable, "Handle Results", to define the function
that was later passed as a call-back to "Git-Stuff".
This is certainly viable; however, strictly abiding by this approach will leave you
with many, many functions that are only used once in your code.
For simple call-backs, or those that are only referenced once,
it is very common to use anonymous functions as call-backs.
In this case, the anonymous function is defined
within the parameter list of the calling function.
Here's an example of the previous "Handle Results" function being added to the
"Git-Stuff" parameter list as an anonymous function.
Another benefit I've found when using anonymous functions is that they benefit
from JavaScript's support of closures.
As you cascade down a series of functions and call-backs, you continue to have
at your disposal all the variables created along the way.
Let's take a look at some simple examples of writing asynchronous
"JavaScript" in "Node.js" using call-backs.