Okay, so now we're going to take a look
at writing some asynchronous code for "Node.js" using call-backs.
To start, we're going to keep it simple.
For now, what I want to focus on is the function call and the call-back,
so what I have here is a function.
And the way that it works is it will double the number you pass in only
if the number you pass in is even.
If you pass it in as even, it will double it;
if you pass in an odd number, you're going to get an error.
And each call to "Even Doubler" is going to take a random amount of time,
some time less than one second but it's random each time.
If I want to invoke the function "Even Doubler", I can call it here.
I pass in the number that I want to double, and then the call-back
to receive the results when the call is done.
And this is where this random amount of time comes into play.
That's when "Handle Results" will be called.
And the function "Handle Results" takes three parameters.
Now when we looked at the slides, the convention that we looked at is that the first parameter
to the call-back is whether or not there was an error,
and you'll see here we have a variable called "ERR".
And after that, I mean, you can really have as many parameters as you want
in your call-back, and so in this case I have two.
One is I have the results, which will be the doubled number if there wasn't an error.
And then I have a third parameter, which is how long did it take this particular invocation
of "Even Doubler" to run?
Here we inspect "Error", and if we find an error, we log that to the console either way.
And then if there's not an error, we tell you what the results are
and then how long it took to calculate those results.
So if we invoke here for an even number, let's see what we get.
We'll run it.
We got our dashed line here; that printed first.
Even though we invoked the function first, the first thing to the console was our dashed line.
And that's because the invocation, it was going to take a certain amount of time to complete.
And while that was completing, "Node" went ahead and printed out to the console this dashed line.
And then, when "Even Doubler" was done doing its work, it called the "Handle Results" call-back,
which inspected the error value, and it was null in this case, which is what we would want to see
because this is indeed an even number.
And then it printed out to the console the fact
that the number 2 doubled is 4, and it took 604 milliseconds.
Now, like I said, that number is random.
If we run it again, you're going to get a different number.
So that's what that looks like.
Now let's try and type in another one right underneath it (typing on keyboard).
This time, we will give it an odd number, which should trigger an error.
And we'll do both.
Okay, now the first one that we called with 2 came back with the result of 4
at 378 milliseconds, and the call where we passed in the 3 generated an error,
and the error message -- so if you'll notice here, we checked for the error and we printed
out the message from that error object and got "Odd Input", so that was the error.
Let's add another one and (typing on keyboard) -- and we'll say that and run it.
Now we got -- this is kind of interesting, right, so we got three results
because we invoked it three times.
The results that we got back are not in the same order in which we invoked the functions.
We called "Event Doubler" with -- and passed it in 2.
Then we immediately called "Event Doubler" again, passed it in 3, and then 10,
and came down and none of them had finished,
so we printed "Console.log" here, which gave us the five dashes.
The first of the three to complete was this one where we passed
in a number 2, gave us back 4 with 737.
The second one to complete -- between the invocation with 3 and the invocation with 10 --
the second one to complete was actually this one, and so that's what was printed
to the console, and then the third one to complete was where we passed
in number 3 and we got the error.
The reason that they're different in this particular case is
because each one's waiting a random amount of time, and it just so happened
that the invocation where we passed in a 3 randomly got the highest of the three numbers,
and so that's how long it waited.
When you're dealing with the asynchronous code like this,
you don't control when the call-back is going to get invoked.
And if you're executing a series of calls to a function, whether like I'm doing one
after the other, or if you were doing them in a "for loop", you can't guarantee
that they're going to get called.
In fact, the call-backs will not get called in the order that you invoked the functions.
Okay, so here what I've done is I've taken our "Even Doubler" function call,
put it inside of a "for loop" where I'm going to call it 10 times.
Just so we'll know what's happening each time I call it, I'm printing out to the console
that I'm about to call it, and the value I'm going to call it for.
( Typing on Keyboard )
So if we move this up, you'll see here they're being invoked in order as it iterates
through the "for loop", and then here's our dashed line that --
but the results come back in a very random order, obviously.
So this would have been where we called it where the counter was 6 and 2 and 4 and 8, and so,
in this case,, they're coming back in what would seem like a random order,
but if you look at the timing, this confirms the fact that the timings were actually in order.
So let's say I wanted to print the message "Done"
at the bottom when this was completely done.
If I were to change this from a named function to an anonymous function,
and keep a count of the call-backs, I might have better luck with that so let's give that a try.
Okay, so now you'll notice that the named function is gone and it's been replaced here
with an anonymous function that I defined as a part of the call to "Even Doubler".
So now as I go through the "for loop", I'm calling "Even Doubler",
passing in the parameter, and then defining an anonymous function to handle as the call-back.
And this part of the call-back is the same as before, but now I'm doing one more thing.
I've initialized a counter to zero here outside of the "for loop", and then as I loop
through the invocations of the call-back, I am incrementing a count.
And then if I'm on the 10th call-back, I know I'm done.
It doesn't necessarily matter which variable this was invoked with,
but I know that I'm counting the number of times that the call-back has been invoked.
And if it's been invoked 10 times, then I'm done.
So let's run this and see if that works.
We see our invocations in order, as before, and we see our call-backs out of order as far
as the numbers they were invoked with, but they are in order by time.
That matches as before.
And now our "Done" is printed at the bottom of the output.
We can take a quick look at what's inside "Even Doubler" and see how that was written,
so what it's doing is calculating an amount of time to wait.
And if what was passed in is odd, then it's going to use
that "Set Time-out" function and say, "You know what?
After that period of time that you just calculated, I want you to call back an error."
And then if the number is even, it's going to say, "Well, you know what?
After that amount of time that you just calculated, I want you to call back,
but I don't want you to pass it back at the error.
In fact, I want you to pass a null for the error parameter; go ahead and double it,
and then pass back the wait time."
So this is where we get the multiple parameters in the successful call-back.