Now that we've learned how to write code using anonymous call-backs,
we should also be careful not to overdo it.
Selecting the right combination of approaches can be crucial
in structuring your "Node.js" application.
Anonymous functions are very common and very useful, but many novice "Node" developers,
who rely on them exclusively, find themselves frustrated with the Christmas tree problem.
Code like this can be difficult to debug and maintain.
This is often cited as a shortcoming of Node's programming model.
However, the smart use of named functions, as well as modules, event emitters and streams,
all of which we'll cover in subsequent videos, will give you the tools you need to write
"Node" applications that are no more difficult to build and maintain than those
of any other server-side programming language.
And besides, they're much more fun.
So to conclude, in this module, we began with a brief introduction
to the origins of "Node" and its underpinnings.
We next installed "Node" in a "Linux" environment using "NVM".
After that, we took a brief lap
around the features offered by the "Cloud9" web-based "IDE".
Diving into the fundamentals, we then discussed Node's event loop and non-blocking IO.
We finished with a discussion of using call-backs to write asynchronous code.
I hope this module has been a useful introduction to "Node.js".
I encourage you to stick around as we dig deeper
into this exciting server-side programming framework.
Thank you.