Paul O'Fallon: Hello, my name is Paul O'Fallon and I'd like to welcome you
to the course An Introduction to Node.js Module 4, Accessing the Local System.
In this module we'll examine the ways Node gives you to interact with your local environment.
This includes Node's "process" object, interacting with the file system,
which will lead us to a brief conversation on Node's buffer class
and then we'll wrap up with a look at the os module.
So, let's get started (silence).
The "process" object provides a way for your Node application to both manage its own process
as well as other processes on the system.
It's available by default in your Node application; it does not need to be required.
The "process" object contains a variety of variables and functions including a set
of streams for accessing standard in, out and error.
The first is a readable stream and the latter two are writable streams.
It also provides a series of attributes about the current process such as its set
of environment variables, command line arguments, process ID and title,
uptime and memory usage, current working directory and more.
It provides a set of functions.
Most of these such as abort, change directory,
set gid and uid act on the current running process.
The kill function however requires a process ID as a parameter and can be used
to terminate other processes on the system.
Finally, the "process" object is an instance of the event emitter class.
It emits an exit event when the process is about to exit.
It can also emit an uncaught exception event
if an exception bubbles all the way up to the event loop.
It also emits all of the standard POSIX signal events such as SIGNI etcetera.
Let's take a look at some examples of using Node's process module (silent).