So, for our first process example we're going to take a look at the three streams
that are provided by the "process" object.
Now, we spent a lot of time looking at streams in an earlier module, so I'm not going to go
into the ins and outs of streams themselves and in fact
in that earlier module we did use the process dot standard out stream in our examples.
But what we're going to do here is look at a modified version of an example
from the Node.js documentation and we're going to try to hit on all three of the streams;
standard in, standard out and standard error.
And so what we're doing here is we're going to actually be listening for data coming
in on standard in and when it does we're going to turn around and write it to standard out
and when the standard in stream is closed we're going
to write another message, but this time to standard error.
So these are the underlying events and functions that make up the stream interface,
but here we're interacting with them directly as opposed to say piping to or from one of these.
Another thing about standard in is that this stream starts paused, so you must call resume
in order for it to begin receiving information.
So we're going to run this, but in Cloud9 we're going to run this differently
than we've run some of our previous examples.
If you look down in the lower right hand corner you'll see an open a terminal button
and if you click on that what you'll actually get is in your tabbed interface,
you will get another tab that is an actual terminal session into your workspace.
And so since we want our process to read from standard in,
we really need to run in it a shell.
And so, this will give us the ability to do that and so we're
down inside the appropriate directory, so let's run our script (typing).
And so now as we type into standard in (typing) you'll see that we are triggering the event
which in turn is causing us to write to standard out.
And so for as long as we were to do this we would continue to see the data be read
by standard in and written to standard out.
And then if we do a control D to exit out of the program you'll see the end
which was printed to standard error.
This program worked like we expected, it was listening for when I typed in hello and world,
it triggered these data events on standard in where we turned around and wrote to standard out
and then my control D ended the standard in stream which caused the end event where we wrote
to standard error that we're ending.
So now we're going to take a look at some of the events provided by the "process" object.
We've taken most of the code from our earlier example and copied it here.
So we still have our standard in, standard out, standard error code from before
but we've added a couple of extra items.
Now we're also listening for one of the POSIX signals, we're listening for SIG term
and if we receive that event we're going to write to standard error
and we've also added a console dot log statement here
to log the process ID of this particular process.
So let's run this and see if we can trigger this SIG term event.
So we're going to run the program here (typing).
And, remember the one line we added for the console dot log to print
out the process ID -- that's what this is here.
Now, if we interact with it, it works the same as it did before all the way down to
if we do control D it will end, but we don't want to do that so let's run it again.
So now what we'd like to do is see if we can cause the SIG term event to happen.
So to do that what we're going to do is actually do is go to another terminal window
and issue a kill command to this process and see if we can trigger that.
So this is process 10200 and so if we go here (typing)
and from the UNIX command line issue the kill command dash term and put in the process ID
of our Node process, when we go back - so you can see here,
"Why are you trying to terminate me?"
So us running the kill command from the command line
and specifying dash term caused these SIG term event to be emitted from the "process" object
which then invoked our function and we printed this to standard error.
Now, the program itself is still running
so we can still interact with it and control D to end it.