Interacting with the file system in Node is done via the built in fs module.
Many of the functions provided by this module are wrappers around the POSIX functions.
They come in both asynchronous and synchronous flavors.
This is the one area of the Node standard library
where you will see a significant collection of synchronous functions.
The fs module also provides a couple of stream oriented functions;
create ReadSream opens a file for reading and returns a readable stream,
create WriteStream opens a file for writing and returns a writable stream.
These are useful for integrating with other streams as we did in our last module.
Lastly, the fs module provides a watch function
which will watch a file or directory for changes.
The function returns and event emitter which emits a change event whenever a file changes.
Let's take a look at interacting with a file system using the fs module (silence).