In demonstrating interacting with the file system we're going to look
at both the synchronous and asynchronous functions provided by the fs module
and we're going to start with the synchronous functions.
Now each of the synchronous functions has the word sync in the name at the end
of the function name and so you'll see that repeated over and over again here.
We start by requiring the fs module and from there we check to see
if the temp directory exists and if it does we check to see if new dot text is
in that directory and if it is we remove that new dot text file
and then we remove the directory temp.
This lets us run this script over and over again because it cleans up after itself.
We make the directory temp, we check to be sure that the directory exists
and if it does we change into that directory, then we create a file called test dot text
and pass in this stream to be the contents of the file, then we rename the file,
then we print the size of the file and the contents of the file.
And so this is very top down, these are the synchronous functions
and so each one executes one after the other, no call backs.
So let's run this (silence).
So if we look at the output it says the directory exists removing,
which means that it did find the temp directory and then it comes down here
and creates the file, renames it and then tells us that the file has a size of 35 bytes
and that this is some test text from the file is the contents.
So it's written to test dot text and then renamed
to new dot text and then that's the contents.
Now that we've seen what this logic looks like implemented with the synchronous functions,
let's take a look at the same logic implemented using the asynchronous version
of these functions.
So now we're looking at the asynchronous functions provided by the fs module.
Here we've left our cleanup code at the top using the synchronous version
because that's really just to kind of remove the previous invocations of this script.
So before we even go through each line of the code you're probably thinking that this looks
like the Christmas tree problem and you would be right.
This code implemented just like this, all just with anonymous functions
as callbacks does create a Christmas tree problem and no,
I would not want to maintain code that looks like this
for anything longer than a demonstration.
But it is a good example and actually a tangible example
of what a Christmas tree problem can look like.
You'll notice that the word sync is gone from all of the function names
and so here we're making the directory temp
and in the callback we are calling the exists, to be sure that it exists.
And in that callback we get whether or not it exists, so we'll check and be sure
that it does exist and if it does we change into the directory, we write the file,
we rename the file, we get the statistics for the file to get the size,
print that to the console and then we read the file and get the data
and then we print out the contents of the file.
Each one of these is building on the one prior by being implemented
in the prior functions callback which gives us the Christmas tree.
But let's run this and see what we get (silence).
So if we look at the results we get basically the same output as before.
This is an example of what it would look like to use the asynchronous functions in comparison
to the synchronous functions for accessing the file system.