In one of our last demos you may remember that we had to invoke a two string method
on the value returned when we read a file from the file system.
That's because the return value for this function was a buffer object.
So what's a buffer?
JavaScript has difficulty dealing with binary data,
but interacting with the network and file systems require it.
The buffer class provides a raw memory allocation
for dealing with binary data directly.
Buffers can be converted to and from strings by providing an encoding.
The default encoding is utf8.
When we called two string on our buffer returned
from reading a file we were using this default encoding to convert it to a string.
This support for multiple encodings makes buffers a handy way
to convert strings to and from base64.
Let's take a look at a couple of examples using buffers (silence).