So now we're going to take a look at a couple of examples of using buffers.
But before we go through this code I want to pop back to the file system examples
from the last demo and point out where buffers were showing up.
Either in the asynchronous or the synchronous example,
you'll notice that when we read the file from disc we take the value that is returned
by the read file sync function and we call a two string on it.
So that means what we're getting back is actually not a string by default
and so we're calling two string on the instance of the buffer object
to get a string value to print out.
This is an example of where you're getting a buffer
and you need to be able to deal with buffers.
A couple of canned examples here where we are instantiating a new buffer and passing
in the string hello, this gives us a buffer B. If we want to log it to the console just
like we saw in our file system example we'll convert it to a string.
We can also convert it to a base64 string by simply passing
in the encoding base64 in the two string function.
Because of what's returned from each of these function calls,
you can actually chain this together.
So here you see I'm actually creating a buffer passing in world
and then immediately converting it to base64.
So if all you really wanted to do is get the word world
as a base64 encoded string you could do all that in one line.
So something else you can do very efficiently with buffers is call
out certain subsections of a buffer.
So in this case we're going to pull out the first few characters
of this buffer and print that to the console.
So now let's run this and see what we get.
So looking at our output we see first, we see hello which is our buffer we instantiated here
with the string hello and then converted back to a string.
And the next console dot log output is
where we log the base64 encoded version of hello which is here.
Here we log to the console the two string
where we only wanted the first two characters which gave the H-E of hello.