We first saw the os module back during our discussion of using require
to include built-in modules in our Node applications.
The os module provides several functions for examining the operating system
on which your Node application is running.
These include the default temp directory, the host name, the type of os, the platform,
architecture and release information.
They also include the uptime of the system, the load average, total and free memory,
the number of CPU's, as well as a list of networking interfaces.
Finally, the EOL variable contains the appropriate end
of line marker for the operating system.
So, to conclude; in this module we've looked at several ways Node allows you to interact
with your local environment including Node's "process" object,
the fs module for the file system,
a short diversion to discuss buffers and a recap of the os module.
I hope this has been a helpful look into the local system features provided by Node.js.
Thank you.