Paul O'Fallon: Hello, my name is Paul O'Fallon, and I'd like to welcome you
to the course, An Introduction to Node.js, Module 6, Testing and Debugging.
In this module, we'll discuss basic unit testing using Node's built in "assert" module,
and quickly move on to more advanced testing with the Mocha test framework and should.js.
And we'll wrap up by using the Cloud9 IDE to debug Node.js applications.
So let's get started.
"Assert" is a module that comes with Node, but must be required by your application.
It provides functions to perform a number of tests or assertions in your code.
For example, you can test for equality or inequality between expected and actual values.
You can test whether a block of code does or does not throw an exception.
You can test to the truthiness of a value.
Because of Node's conventions on the placement of the error parameter in a callback,
there is also special support for testing whether an error was passed to a callback.
And each of these assertions can contain a message to output when the assertion fails.
When testing for equality, the "assert" module provides for three different types of equality.
The first is simply the equal function.
This is a shallow coercive test for equality,
and is equivalent to using the double equal sign in JavaScript code.
The second is strict equal, which, as the name indicates, is strict equality,
the equivalent of a triple equal sign in JavaScript.
The third and final type of equality provided by "assert" is deep equal.
This allows you to test the equality of more complex data types.
In this case, identical values are equal,
and other values that are not objects are evaluated with coercive equality.
Date objects are considered equal if they contain the same date and time.
And other objects, including arrays, are considered equal if they have the same number
of owned properties, equivalent values for every key, and an identical prototype.
Let's take a look of some examples of using "assert" to unit test our Node.js code.