(Pause) So now we're going to take a look at an example of using "assert"
to unit test some Node.js code, and to do that we're going to bring up our mathfun module,
that we created in Module 2 of this course.
And in fact we've extended it a little bit to include a synchronous version
of the same evenDoubler function that we used back then.
So here in our mathfun.js file, you'll see the evenDoubler function, which I've folded here,
but it's the exact same code from Module 2, but we've added a synchronous version
of this function called evenDoublerSync, which has the same rules as far
as requiring an even number, but instead of invoking a callback,
it returns the value if it is past an even number.
And rather than passing an error to a callback in case
of an odd number, it throws an exception.
In this case it throws an exception with a new error with the text odd input.
I've added them both to module exports here, so they're both available to my code.
So now I'm going to back to the unit test for this code.
We see here that I have required the "assert" module, and I've required my mathfun script
in the same directory, and assigned it to the variable "fun".
So now the test code is that I am running the synchronous version of evenDoubler passing it
in a two, and asserting that that will be equal to four.
And then to test, what will happen if I pass in an odd number to the synchronous function?
I'm asserting that if I pass in an odd number to evenDoublerSync
that that will throw an exception.
And then this extra parameter here, I can actually specify a regular expression to match
to the text of the error that's returned.
So if you remember from the mathfun file, I'm returning odd input.
So what I'm actually checking for here is that the exception
that is thrown should have the word odd in it.
So to test the asynchronous evenDoubler function, I'm invoking it with a value of two,
passing it an anonymous callback, and then checking to see if an error was returned.
And then I'm also asserting that the results are indeed equal to four as they should be.
And then in this case, I've actually supplied an extra message to the "assert" function
that this is what it should print out if this test fails.
And lastly, I'm testing the asynchronous function when I pass it in an odd value.
So in this case, I do expect the error to come back not null,
so I'm asserting that I'm going to get an error back.
So let's run this code and see what we get.
(Pause) As you can see, I didn't get any errors, but I really didn't get any output either.
So the "assert" module is really just
for testing your output and for exceptions and whatnot.
It doesn't really give you any useful feedback, particularly if everything passes.
So let's make some of these tests fail.
Why don't we go here and change the string that we're matching
on for the exception that's thrown, and let's run this.
(Pause) So you can see I got a rather messy error message, but what it's telling me is
that odd input is what the error contained, and that is not what I was testing for;
I was looking for odd two, and that was not there.
So let's fix this one.
And now let's go down and make this one fail.
So now we're going to say that when I call evenDoubler with a value of two,
I should get five back, which we know is not right, but that's going to fail.
So if we run this, here you'll see that we did get our message, evenDoubler failed
on an even number, so that's our message here.
It's kind of in the middle of you know some extra stuff,
this output is certainly decipherable, but it's not very friendly, but it is there.