A Node application of any complexity will quickly outgrow the built
in test capabilities provided by the "assert" module.
There are many test frameworks that have sprouted up in the Node community.
A fairly popular test framework is Mocha.
It is also common to see it paired with should.js,
which provides a rich assertion syntax.
Mocha provides many useful features for writing tests for your Node application.
Even when testing asynchronous functions, it will run your tests, serially.
Like test frameworks for many other languages, the test cases are organized into test suites.
There are hooks to execute arbitrary code before and after each test suite,
as well as before and after each test.
It includes the support for pending, exclusive and inclusive tests.
A pending test is one that has been stubbed out, but not yet implemented.
Exclusive and inclusive tests are helpful ways to isolate certain tests without having
to comment out those tests, which you may forget to uncomment later.
It will time each one of your tests, and let you know which ones are running slow.
During your development cycle, it can be configured to watch your source directory,
and rerun the tests each time a file changes, for example, when you save a file
in your IEE or in your text editor.
It even supports multiple syntax options for writing your tests
and multiple options for rendering the test results.
Should.js extends Node's asserts module
with behavior driven development or BDD style assertions.
These can make your tests easier to construct and much more readable.
Here is an example from the should.js read me file.
You'll notice that we have a user object with two properties, name and pets.
Should.js actually extends the object prototype and adds a should function.
It also adds additional functions, which serve as syntactic sugar,
which make the test more readable.
Here we are saying that the variable user should have a property with the value tj.
Property is an enhanced assertion that understands how
to validate whether an object has a certain property.
You can also chain these assertions to make your tests more compact.
Here we're saying that the user should have a property of pets,
and that the length of that array should be four.
In this case, the test will not blow
up if the user object does not have a pets property, it will just fail.
Even though should is added as a function onto every object, you will still have the case
where you need to check the existence of an object.
In this scenario, you cannot simply append the should option to the end of an object name
because if the object is undefined, it will generate an error.
In this case, you can evoke the should function statically
and pass in the variable to be tested.
The should function is not only available on the top level function,
but on properties of objects as well.
Let's take a look of some examples of testing with Mocha and should.js.