So now let's take a look at writing the same tests we showed earlier using the
"assert" module, but now using Mocha and should.js.
So here is that test file, and we'll notice at the top that we are requiring should to bring it
into this program, but we're not requiring Mocha.
Mocha is actually installed globally on our system, and is what we will run
from the command line, but it's not something we explicitly require here.
But it is what provides the describe and it functions here in the tests themselves.
So let's walk through this.
The describe are basically our test suites, and they can be nested.
So here we're saying that I have some tests for mathfun, and the first set of tests is
that when I'm using the module synchronously, and now I'm defining individual tests here.
It should double even numbers correctly.
This is kind of nice because the tester are self documenting and by writing these descriptions,
somebody coming along later should have a pretty good idea of what it's supposed to do,
even if they're still a little new to the code itself.
So I'm saying it should double even numbers correctly.
Here is where should.js comes in.
If I say fun.evendoublersync, and I'm passing in the number two, I can immediately say
on the return value it should and then dot equal four,
so when I call evenDoublerSync two, it's going to return a value.
And I'm simply saying that should equal four, so I can do all that on one line.
Now my next test, I'm saying that on an odd number it should throw an exception.
And so here I'm executing this function,
and I'm saying that that function should throw an exception, and that exception
in the message should have the word odd.
So that regular expression is similar to our last example.
Now in this case, I'm calling a don function, and don is what's passed into my test.
This is the way that we let Mocha know that this particular test is done,
and for our asynchronous tests that we're about to get to don becomes even more important.
So let's look now, we have another test suite here identified by describe,
and we're saying when evenDoubler is used asynchronously,
it should double even numbers correctly.
And here we're calling our asynchronous function evenDoubler,
passing in a two, and an anonymous callback.
And now if you remember from the slides, we mentioned that if you need
to check the existence of a variable, you can use the should function statically,
which is what we're doing in this case.
So we're saying should not exist error.
We couldn't really say error dot should dot not exist because if it was undefined,
then that would blow out the script, but by saying should dot not dot exist error,
we can test to ensure that that doesn't exist, and then the results should equal four.
Now in this case, calling done, which was passed into our test here is our way
of telling Mocha that this test is done.
And throwing down a little further, we'll say that when invoked asynchronously,
it should return an error on an odd number.
And we're calling evenDoubler again, passing in an odd number this time
for our anonymous callback, we're saying that the error should exist,
but the results should not exist, and we're telling it
that after those two assertions, we're done.
And in our case here, since most of our running we've been doing from the run command
at the top, to run Mocha from the command line, what we're actually going to do is go back
to a terminal here in cloud nine.
So here we have a terminal session.
If you're doing this for the first time, you're going to need to install Mocha, and should,
as well, actually, so you'll want to run mpm install dash gmocha to install it globally,
so it'll be available from the command line.
I also need to install the should module, which I just did.
Now let's install Mocha locally.
(Pause) Okay, so now I can run Mocha from the command line
and I get all kinds of usage information back.
So now let's run Mocha against the test that we wrote.
(Typing sounds)
Now you'll see that for the completed tests, we do get some information back there.
It's hard to tell here, but there's four tiny little dots there.
Because we had written four tests, and then at the bottom there's four tests completed,
and how long those tests took to run, but even that might be a little hard to read,
so as we mentioned in the slides, Mocha has multiple ways of outputting the test results.
So let's take a look at another way to report those results.
( Typing on Keyboard )
( Silence )
So here now what we have done is we've said,
I want you to use the reporter called spec, and run the same test.
This is where the strings that we've passed to describe init come in very handy, right,
so it actually prints out that information along with whether each one passed or failed.
And you'll see they all passed, so they all got green checks.
Now we also mentioned that Mocha will time your tests and let you know
if it thinks it's running slowly.
Now you can configure what slowly means, but here we've taken the default.
And going all the way back to Module 2, if you'll remember
that our asynchronous evenDoubler function waits a random amount of time, up to one second.
And so in this case, what it's saying is -- it's printing these in red, saying, look,
383 milliseconds or 659, that's an awful long time, you might want to take a look at that.
So now that we've seen tests that pass, let's take a look at some that fail.
So let's go back and make a couple of these fail.
So we will go back and change our testing of the error message
that comes in when we throw an exception.
So we'll change that, and then let's come back and we'll do the same one we did before.
We'll make this test say that evenDoubler shall return for two should return five,
even though we know that's not true.
It will make that fail.
So let's save this and then run those.
( Silence )
So let's scroll back up.
You see right here, up at the top, we get the green check for the two that passed,
and we get red for the two that failed.
And then in our summary here it says that two of four tests failed.
Now what it's done, as well, is for the two that failed, it has reprinted them
at the bottom here, and included the stack trace with each one.
It says this was the first test that failed, that's why it gives a number one.
It should have thrown in odd numbers, and that comes back down here
and tells us exactly what happened.
It says that we were trying to match odd two, but got odd input.
And then for our second failed test, if we scroll down,
we'll see expected four to equal five.
Much more digestible information coming out of Mocha
than we were getting just from the pure "assert" module.
Not to say you couldn't have continued to add more and more text and verbage and stuff to the
"assert" module, but sticking with something
like Mocha gives you much better output right off the bat.
We'll take a look at one more feature.
You remember when we talked about isolating tests?
And you can do that with "the only."
So for instance, if I'm really wanting to focus
on this particular test right now, I can come in here and put only.
And that is an inclusive test, meaning I only want to run this one test right now.
So let's say that.
Now, I haven't changed anything else in my test suite, just added that only statement.
And (typing sounds) now it just runs that one test.
So that can be handy for focusing on one particular test.
And we can go back and do the opposite, (typing sounds) and tell it we want to skip that test.
And if we run it again...
( Typing )
( Silence )
When you skip it, it actually turns into a pending test.
Had I simply commented that out, I may have forgotten to uncomment it,
and that test would just be gone, basically.
So if it were failing right now, and I said, well, I'm going to get to it in a minute,
I could simply go in and skip it, it will continue to tell me that it's in pending status
to remind me to go back and fix it.
Once you have a few tests written, it can also be fun to experiment with some
of the different reporters that come with Mocha.
Here is one that's there just for fun, which shows your tests represented
as a plane coming in for a landing.
So as you can see, Mocha not only makes writing tests easier.
It can actually make them fun as well.