Node.js provides hooks for debugging your applications.
And the Cloud9 IDE makes good use of them and their debugging tools.
Here in this screenshot, you can see the breakpoint in line 31,
as well as the value of the data variable.
The window on the right shows the current call stack.
In fact, the buttons along the right side of the window make up Cloud9's debugging functions,
including options to resume as well as step into, over and out of the code being executed.
View the call stack, which you can see here in the screenshot.
Execute arbitrary JavaScript during your debug session.
View the values of currently active variables,
and the ability to manage the breakpoints in your application.
Even more powerful is combining this server side Node.js debugging
with the client side JavaScript debug capabilities of the Chrome web browser.
The two of these together make a powerful JavaScript debug suite.
Let's take a look at some examples of debugging Node applications.