For our first debugging example, we're going to pull up some code
that we looked at in the very first module.
We're going to look at our setTimeout example.
And so what we'll do here is add a breakpoint inside the named function
that gets invoked by a setTimeout.
So we'll simply click here to add a breakpoint to line two.
And when you're running a program in Cloud9 and you want to run it in debug mode,
you can come up here and choose run in debug mode.
And so now when we click the green star button, it will be in debug mode.
So let's run this.
So here we can see that running was printed to the console,
which is our console.log statement here, and then after 200 milliseconds,
when the handleTimeout function was invoked,
our breakpoint was triggered on console.log, and it stopped.
And so here you can see, if we run our mouse over the code we can inspect certain variables,
and we now have this panel available to us over here with some debugging functions.
And so here are our resume, step over, into, and out options, as well as the call stack,
which this program doesn't have much going on, so the call stack is fairly small.
And we can interact with the code or view the variables or the breakpoints.
I only have the one breakpoint in my code right now.
So if we go back up and continue,
then the console.log statement executes, and the program is done.
Now let's pull up another one of our previous examples, a more complicated one,
and look at the debugging functions we can use with that application.
So this is our WebSockets example from Module 5.
Here we're going to scroll down and add a breakpoint whenever we log
to the console upon receiving an event that something was submitted from the browser.
So let's put a breakpoint there and we'll run this once again in debug mode.
And we'll launch our web page.
There's our timer data being updated.
Now let's submit something.
( Typing on Keyboard )
So now that we've submitted it, let's go back to the server.
Our breakpoint was triggered and it has stopped.
And we have the same options here as before.
We have a lot more going on in our call stack this time.
And we have our variables.
Now, here is the variable data set to this is a test, and that is this variable right here.
In fact, if we come up here, simply by running your mouse over it, you can see the value.
This is what we typed in in the web browser, and it's available to be inspected here.
And it stopped.
Now, if we just resume, and then we look down in the (typing sounds) --
you'll see "submitted this is a test" in the output.
That is an example of debugging just on the server side.
But now since we're running in Chrome, we actually have access
to some very nice debugging capabilities on the client side, as well.
So let's take a look at using both of those together.
So now we're going to leave our breakpoint where it is on the server side,
and let's go take a look at the client side.
So if we load up the Chrome developer tools,
we can see that this is the HTML and JavaScript of our web page.
And here I can actually add a breakpoint as well on the client side.
So what I'd like to do is add a breakpoint on the client side before we emit the submit event.
So let's click here to add a breakpoint here.
And so now, as our timer continues to update, let's go and enter a new piece
of information here (typing sounds) and click submit.
Okay, now you can see that we've triggered the breakpoint
in the browser right before we emit the data to the server.
The server side is still running, but the browser side has paused right on the emit.
If we want to continue through this breakpoint, we can come up here, but now if we go back
to our server, now we've tripped our breakpoint on the server, which was on the receipt
of that submit event that we just emitted on the browser.
And this looks like what we saw before,
so if we resume here we'll see our submitted a second test was written to the output.
So this is a demonstration of how you can use the server side debugging capabilities
of Cloud9, alongside the client side debugging capabilities of the Chrome web browser
to provide a full featured debugging environment.