There are other ways to debug Node applications in cases where you are not using the Cloud9 IDE.
There is a Node inspector module, which provides browser based debugging
of Node.js debugging applications.
I touch on this option in another Pluralsight course, Node on Windows in Azure.
So to conclude, in this module, we started with an overview of Node's built
in "assert" module used for writing unit tests of Node.js code.
We then moved on to a more useful and feature rich method
of writing tests using Mocha and should.js.
We then wrapped up by debugging our Node applications using the features found
in the Cloud9 IDE.
I hope this module has been helpful in introducing you to the testing
and debugging features of Node.js.
Thank you.
( Silence )