Hello, my name is Paul O'Fallon and I'd like to welcome you to the course An Introduction
to Node.js, module 7, Scaling Your Node Application.
In this module, we'll cover how to create child processes in your Node application.
And then, we'll look at Node's experimental "cluster" module
for scaling your application across multiple processes.
So, let's get started.
One common criticism of Node applications is
that they do not handle CPU intensive tests well.
This is because spending too much CPU time on any one task
in your Node app will block the event loop and prevent other work from being done.
One strategy for dealing with this issue is the use of "child processes".
A CPU intensive task, resizing an image for example,
can be deferred to a child process while the main Node application continues
to process events.
Node has four ways to launch child processes and all are a part of the child process module.
The first is the spawn function which will launch a new process
and run the command specified in the first parameter.
An optional array of arguments will be passed to the command.
This function returns an instance of a ChildProcess object which is an EventEmitter.
It emits exit and close events which can be listened for by the parent Node application.
The child process return value also has streams for the standard in,
out, and error of the child process.
The parent or spawning process can pipe data to and from these streams much
like you would the similar streams provided by the process object.
The second way to launch a child process in Node is with the exec function.
This function runs the provided command in a shell.
Any command line arguments you wish to provide must be included
in the string past as the command to execute.
You can even pipe between Unix commands within a single invocation of exec. For example,
piping the output of LS to the Unix grep command.
A third method is the execFile function.
This is similar to exec but instead of launching a process and executing the command,
the file parameter is executed directly.
One final method for invoking a child process in Node is particularly optimized
for spawning new child Node processes.
This is done with the fork function.
It is a specialized version of the spawn function especially for creating Node processes.
Like spawn, it returns an instance of the ChildProcess object.
However, in this case, it adds an additional send function and message event
to facilitate message passing between the parent and child processes.
Let's take a look at some sample code from the Node.js website that uses the fork function.
Here we have a parent.js script which requires the child process module.
It then calls the fork function to invoke Node again to run the child.js script.
It listens for the message event
from the returned ChildProcess object logging the message to the console.
It then attempts to send a message to the newly forked Node process.
When the separate Node process runs child.js, it listens for the message event
and logs the message to the console.
It too attempts to send a message back to its parent.
Each process sends its message which is picked up by the other and logged to the console.
Let's take a look at some examples of launching child processes in Node.js.