For our first child process example, we're going to take a look at the exec function.
And so here you can see that we've required the child process module
and in more specifically the exec function directly.
And so, what we're going to do is run the uptime Unix function and in the callback,
if we get an error, we will log that to the console,
otherwise we will log the output to the console.
And so what this will be is the output of the command once the command has completed.
And down here, we're going to log to the console the process ID of the child process.
So starting with just a simple uptime command, let's run this.
Before we get any results from the child process,
we are logging to the console the process ID and you can see that here.
And then we get the output of the uptime command printed to the console
where the output is and then the results.
But this can be more than just a simple Unix command,
it could be any arbitrary Unix statement.
So for instance, if we were to pipe the uptime command to the cut command
and slice just a little bit of that output to display, you could do that here
and then everything else would work the same.
So let's run this.
And if you want to compare that to the last output,
you can see here where in our earlier output,
we received the entire output of the uptime command.
But because the actual command we sent to the child process was uptime and then pipe
that to cut, we only got a little bit of the output the next time.
Now let's change the commands being run to force it to generate an error
so we can see what that looks like.
So, if I change the name of this cut command to be 23cut which doesn't exist, we'll run that
and see what the error looks like.
So here you can see we output the process ID again but in this case,
because we detected an error,
instead of printing standard out, we printed standard error.
And what standard error told us is that 23cut is a command
that our shell does not know anything about.
So this is an example of using exec to execute an arbitrary command on your system.