For our next child process example, we'll take a look at the spawn function.
Now the spawn function gives you more control over the standard in, standard out,
and standard error of your process while it's running.
If you remember in our exec example, we had access to standard out
and standard error once the process was complete.
In this case, you can actually feed data to standard in and get data from standard
out while the process is running.
So in this example, we're spawning two processes, one is the Unix PS command
to get a list of processes and another command is the grep command
and we want to look for the phrase Node.
Now because the child processes have standard out, standard error and standard in as streams,
we can actually pipe from one to the other.
And so what we've done here is said I'm going to take the standard out of the PS command
and pipe it to standard in of grep.
In essence, doing a Node what you would otherwise maybe do from the Unix command line
and then saying, I'm going to take the standard out of grep and send it to the console.
But of course even though we are piping up here, you can also watch
for events on the streams as well.
So here, we're looking for a data event on standard error to see if there's an error
with the PS command and if there is, we will log that to the console, and the same for grep here.
So let's run this.
So here you can see the command has run and what was printed to the console was the output
of the PS command piped through grep.
Here you can see node and node so these are commands that passed
through grep because they contain node.