So now for our final child process example, we're going to take a look at the fork function.
And if you'll remember, fork is built on spawn but especially designed
for spawning child processes that are also Node applications.
And so here in our example, what we're doing is we're calling fork and asking it
to run honorstudent.js which is another Node program.
And when it executes, fork returns us a ChidProcess object,
and on that ChildProcess object we're going to invoke the send function
which means we're going to send it a message.
And the message we're going to send it is this JSON object which has a command called double
and a number 20, so we're basically asking the child double the number 20.
Now we're also listening for a message from the child and when we get a message,
we're printing the answer variable to the console and then we're sending another message
to the child and this time, the command we're sending is done.
This notion of a command in this JSON object could be whatever you want.
So now let's go look at the code that's been forked.
So our evenDoubler function is showing up again here, but now we've wrapped it inside
of a function that gets invoked whenever this child receives a message.
So in the child process, we're simply registering a function
for the message event on the process object.
So whenever this process receives a message, we're invoking this function.
And in the function, we're going to look at the command.
If you remember, part of the JSON object that we were sending was a CMD variable.
So if the CMD variable is set to double, we're going to log to the console that we were asked
to double this number and then we'll run our-- get all evenDoubler process.
And when we get an answer back, we will use process again to send a message back
to the parent and what we're going to send them is this JSON object
that will contain the result.
Now, if the command that we get is done, then this child process can exit
and so that's what process exit will do.
So let's go back and run this now and see what we get.
The first log to the console is from the honorstudent program where he's telling us
that he was asked to double the number 20, so he received the message with the command double.
The second line is from the parent process where he received the message back from the child
with the answer and he says the answer is 40.
So the main takeaway for this particular example
in the fork function is really the message passing
between the parent and the child process.