Node has recently introduced an experimental cluster module.
This builds on the child process fork function and introduces classes, functions,
and events for managing a master application and a set of "Worker" Nodes.
In a typical cluster scenario, there will be a Node.js script
which serves as the master application.
The cluster module provides a variable isMaster, which will tell you
if your code is running the master process.
To create Worker Nodes, actually separate Node.js processes.
Cluster provides a fork function.
By default, fork will run the same Node.js grep for the worker as the master.
You can use the isMaster variable in a large if statement
to segment the master application from the worker code.
Executing the fork function will also emit a fork event in the master.
Once the worker process has been spawned, the master will also emit an online event indicating
that the worker has been created.
Additional workers can be created with subsequent invocations of the fork function.
Cluster also provides an isWorker variable
to indicate whether your code is executing inside a worker Node.
A common cluster scenario is spawning multiple worker Nodes to create a scalable web server,
if the worker executes a listen function, a listening event is emitted on the master.
And the arguments to this listen function are transmitted to the master
where it will create a listening server for that IP import if one does not already exist,
and pass a handle to this server back to the worker.
If another worker process executes the same listen function,
the master will send the same handle to this second worker.
This allows both workers to listen on the same IP port combination.
It is then up to the operating system
as to how incoming requests are distributed between worker processes.
They do not proxy through the master.
Requests are sent directly to worker processes.
Let's take a look at an example of using the cluster module
to set up a multi worker web server.