Paul O'Fallon: Hello.
My name is Paul O'Fallon, and I'd like to welcome you to the course,
"An Introduction to Node.js, Module 5 -- Interacting with the Web."
In this module, we'll learn how to use Node as a web client, a web server,
and how to extend that to include real time integration using Socket.IO.
So let's get started.
First, we'll look at using Node to make requests of other websites.
In a couple of our earlier videos, we used the third-party request module
to fetch the HTML of the Pluralsight homepage.
Here, we're going to look at doing the same thing using the HTTP module
that is included with Node.
It can be included in your application by requiring HTTP.
The request function provided by the HTTP module takes two parameters --
an options parameter and a callback.
This options parameter can be either a simple URL string,
or a more complex object specifying many options about the request being made.
The request function returns a value, which is an instance of client request.
This is a writable stream and can be written or piped to for HTTP post uploads.
In addition to returning a value, the request function also takes a callback parameter.
This callback, when invoked, is passed a single parameter, and instance of client response
which represents the results of the HTTP request.
This client response is a readable stream which can be read from or piped to a writable stream.
Note that this callback is an example of where Node does not follow its own conventions,
since the first parameter to the callback is not an error indicator.
If you don't pass a callback to the request function,
you can still retrieve the client response object.
It is also provided by a response event emitted
by the client request returned from the function call.
If all you're doing is making a simple get request however,
Node provides a simplified interface in HTTP.git.
Let's take a look at some examples
of using Node's built-in HTTP module for making client requests.