So now we're going to take a look at using Node's HTTP module
to make some HTTP client requests.
In our first example, we're going to come down to this code here
where we're calling HTTP requests, and if you remember,
I mentioned that the first parameter could be either a simple URL or an object.
So for our first run, we're going to use a simple URL and we're going to pass it a callback
to be called when the response is ready and it will pass us the response.
And then we're going to log the status code in the response to the console, which will give us
like a 200 or 404 or 500 the HTTP status code that is returned, and then we're also going
to pipe the response to process.stanardout.
So when calling HTTP requests and being returned the request object,
in order to have the request actually invoked, you have to call a request.end basically,
closing the writeable stream that it's giving you when you create the request.
Let's run this now and see what we get.
And so here you can see in the output that we got the HTML from Google's homepage,
and the JavaScript; and if we scroll (typing) up to the top we see 200, that's the status code
that was returned which is an okay status code.
That is a very simple way to make a request and get your response back.
So now let's make the same request but instead of passing in a simple URL,
let's pass in the options object that we've created here.
It will end up making the same request
but you can see we've defined the values as a set of properties.
So let's substitute out the simple URL for the options variable and run it again
and we should get the same answer.
And we do.
We get the 200 response and then if we scroll through you'll see all
of the HTML and JavaScript we've got before.
So if you know you're going to make a get request,
we can optimize this by just saying "get."
Because you're doing a get, the request that is returned does not have to be closed
because in a get scenario it knows you're not going to be uploading any data,
so you can leave off the request.end, and in fact, you don't even really need
to take the return variable, so you can take that out, as well.
Now, let's run this.
And you can see it did the same thing.
Interestingly enough, so I used Google in this example.
In previous examples, I had used the Pluralsight homepage,
so let's put that in here and see what we get.
( Typing )
Now, this is interesting.
So what we got back was a 301 status code, and the HTML that this object has moved
and can be found at a different URL.
So a difference between the built-in HTTP request and get functions
and the third party module that we used, is that these do not automatically follow redirects
where if you remember in our previous modules when we simply used the third party module
to issue a request against Pluralsight, we got the HTML back.
We didn't even really know that there was a redirect that needed to be followed.
In this particular case, you're operating at a slightly lower level where you would have
to deal with those redirects on your own.