In our very first module of this course, we copied the example web server code
from the node.js.org homepage and used it to stand up a simple server.
Now, we'll take another look at that code and how it leverages many
of the features we've learned so far in this course.
The create server function is passed a single parameter.
The callback to be invoked each time a request is received by the web server.
Optionally if no callback is provided, requests can also be received by listening for events
on the server object that is returned.
Even after the create server function has returned,
the server will not begin accepting HTTP requests until the listen function is called.
This function can be called in several different ways, but the most common is
with an IP port number combination.
When a request is made to the HTTP server
and the callback is invoked, it is passed two parameters.
The first is an instance of server requests, which is a readable stream.
It represents the request being made and for uploads to the server it can be read
from or piped to a writable stream.
The second parameter passed to the callback
on each web request is a server response object, which is a writable stream.
This represents the response sent to the client.
If you are returning steam-oriented data, such as a file from disk, you can pipe that stream
to the server response writable stream.
Support for SSL requests are addressed by a separate HTTPS module,
which has a very similar create server function.
Let's take a look at some examples of using Node's built-in HTTP module
for creating a simple web server.