So now we're going to take a look at using Node to run a simple web server.
Now, this will be a slight extension over what we looked at in our earlier modules
where we simply cut and paste the code from the Node.js homepage,
but we did use that for a starting point here.
We are requiring the HTTP module and then we're calling create server just like before,
and we're passing in a single function which will be invoked on each request.
And if you remember, this function is passed a request and a response.
Now, just like the example from the Node homepage, we're going to write out the header
of 200 for a status code of Okay, and then a content type of "text/plain."
But now we're going to do a little bit more.
If the URL in the request is "/file.txt," we're going to go to the file system,
and we're going to open a readable stream of that file
and we're going to pipe it to the response.
So if you remember, the response was a writeable stream, so we're simply going
to open a file and pipe it to the response.
Otherwise, we're going to call result.end Hello world.
And then rather than a server that's returned being stored as a variable here,
and then simply to turn around and call listen,
the listen is chained to the end of create server.
So we're creating a server and then for the server that's returned,
we're going to call listen and remember our variables for providing port and IP,
we've put those here and then a console.log to show that the server is running.
And just so we can double check what the value of /file.text is, let's take a look at that.
So this is a file being read from the file system and piped to this response.
Now, one more thing I want to point out real quick that may not be familiar to you
yet is this "underscoreunderscoredirname."
That is a variable that will tell you the directory that the current script is running in.
So in this case what I want to say is my server.js is running in this directory,
and I want to find /file.text in the same directory.
So let's run this and try a couple of different URLs.
So we're going to visit the URL here, (typing) and without anything added to the base URL,
we simply get "Hello world," just what we would expect because we didn't ask for /file.text
so we're just going to get "Hello world."
But now, let's ask for /file.text.
And now you can see here that we did get the contents of the file return to the browser.
And so this is a good example of using streams to go from a file system to a network
where we actually opened a file from disk and then simply piped it to the response.