While not a core part of Node, it makes sense to take a few minutes
and follow the web server scenario to its logical next step.
Socket.IO provides an abstraction over the various methods used
to maintain an active connection between a browser and a server.
It will use web sockets where they are supported, and will transparently fall back
to several other techniques in cases where web sockets are not yet supported,
either due to browser or firewall limitations.
In the case of Node.js, Socket.IO also provides a consistent interface
for performing these socket-based communications in both the browser and the server.
This is one tangible demonstration of the synergy
between JavaScript on the client and the server.
Here on the left, we have a snippet of code that would run in Node.js on a server.
Notice that it starts by requiring the Socket.IO module in invoking the listen function.
From there, it is using the event emitter construct to listen to and emit events.
On the browser side, the Socket.IO JavaScript library is loaded from the server.
Notice that there is no special configuration on the server to provide this JavaScript file.
That is handled transparently by the Socket.IO Node.js module.
Now, let's step through a typical back-and-forth scenario.
The browser will issue IO.connect to establish a connection to the Node.js server.
The server receives a connection event and emits a news event with a payload, "Hello world."
The browser receives this news event and invokes the appropriate function.
Within this function, the browser emits an event entitled,
"my other event," and provides some data.
This event is received on the Node.js server and the appropriate function is invoked
which logs the payload data to the console.
The powerful thing about this scenario is that both the browser
and the server are using the same constructs for emitting and acting
on messages being passed back and forth.
The code on the server looks very similar to that in the browser and vice-versa.
During this type of development in other server site languages it's certainly possible,
but it will lack the symmetry and implementation and all the benefits that come with it.
Let's take a quick look at a Socket.IO Node.js example.