So for the first part of our web socket example, we're going to go back
to our Linux VM that we used in Module 1.
And part of the reason for this is because Cloud9 does not support web sockets natively.
And so I wanted to show you this first in an environment that supports web sockets
and then we'll go back to Cloud9 and show you how to get it to work there.
But here in our Linux VM, let's go through the Node server side code
that will be using the web sockets.
We're starting off by requiring HTTP and Socket.IO and the file system.
Now, this example will be a little bit different than what we saw on the slides for Socket.IO
because this will have a web server and Socket.IO server combined.
Our slide only had a Socket.IO server.
Here, you'll see our HTTP create server function, but in this case instead
of passing an anonymous callback, we're passing a handler named function.
And handler, all it really does is says, "Regardless of what URL you give me,
I'm always going to give you back index.HTML"; so it doesn't even really look at the request,
it just simply opens up index.HTML and then returns it.
The server being returned from create server here restoring it in an app variable,
and passing that to Socket.IO.listen, so Socket.IO really adds itself to the server
that was created in HTTP create server.
So for the Socket.IO server, we're saying, "Whenever I receive a connection event,
meaning a browser connects to the server, I want you to set an interval every two seconds.
And every two seconds I want you to capture a current time stamp emitted to the log,
and then over the socket I want you to emit a timer event to the browser and I want you
to pass the time stamp that you just created to the browser."
And also, we want to listen for a submit event that comes from the browser,
and if we receive that we want to take that data and just log it to the console.
And then we're going to call app.listen for the create server that we created up here,
and this is what will serve the index.HTML page and then something to log to the console.
Now before we run this, let's take a look at what is in index.HTML
and will be returned to the browser.
(Typing) So here's a view source of the index.HTML page.
Here you'll see that onload we are making a connection to the server,
we are listening for the timer event and when we get the timer event,
we're going to update a portion of the HTML page to show the data
where the time stamp that came with the timer event.
And then in our submit data function which gets invoked whenever we click on the button
of the form on the page, we're going to get the input data and we're going
to generate a submit event and pass that data along with the event.
So here we are listening for a timer event and emitting a submit event.
And over on the server side, we are emitting a timer event and listening for a submit event.
That's kind of the symmetry that you get when doing this between Node
on a server and JavaScript in the browser.
Now that we've taken a look at it, let's run it and see what it does.
( Typing )
So here it tells us that Socket.IO has been started
and here is our console.log statement telling us the server is running.
So if we go to the test page and hit Refresh, the page has been loaded and now you can see
that we've begun receiving timer events from the server.
If we go back and look at the server logs, you can see this is the console.log we have inside
of that interval where we're logging to the console as well,
and so those timer events continue to be sent to the browser.
Now, if we want to type in something here
to generate the submit event on a server, we can do that.
So if we type in a string here and press "Submit" and then jump back to the server,
you'll see "Submitted colon qwerty" right here, which is the event
on the server triggered by the browser.
This is an example of the back and forth that you can achieve between a server
and a browser via web sockets and Socket.IO without any page refreshes,
without reloading a page or long pulling or anything.
So now we're back in Cloud9 and here I have the same JavaScript file
as I had before on my Linux VM.
I've folded a little bit of the code here just so that it would all fit in one window,
but you can trust me that the code in here is the same as it was on our VM.
The only thing I've changed here is this code here.
So like I mentioned, Socket.IO will try to use web sockets,
and then if it doesn't it will begin to fall back to other transports.
So what I've done here is given it an explicit instruction that says, "You know what,
the only transport I want you to use here is the "xhr-polling."" So I'm going
to use this mechanism to maintain the connection between the client and the server
since I can't depend on web sockets.
These three lines are the only thing I've changed
and let's run it here and see what we get.
So you'll see here very similar output to what we had before and now we can just click on this.
( Typing )
And we'll see, we have our sample webpage and timer events continually updated.
And if we come back here and look,
we'll see that we're getting data continuously written to the output.
Now, let's come type something in here real quick.
(Typing) Now if jump back -- in fact, let's just go and stop the server --
and we look, and I may have to hunt for it but you'll see submitted this as a test.
So even if you know in your production environment,
you'll be able to support web sockets or you'll have a fallback strategy.
In Cloud9 you can just set this and it becomes much easier to do your development that way.